Papers of Morris K. Udall, 1920-1995
University of Arizona Library Special Collections
- Media Files, 1961-1991
  - Photographs, 1956-1990
    - Udall Photographs: Mo Udall Birthday Roast. 1983 (Box 738, Folder 48)
    - Udall Photographs: Udall/New Medical Transport Dedication, Phoenix. 1983 (Box 738, Folder 49)
    - Udall Photographs: Kolb Road Ribbon Cutting, Tucson. November 2, 1984 (Box 738, Folder 50)
    - Udall Photographs: Central Arizona Project Dedication. 1985 (Box 739, Folder 1)
    - Udall Photographs: United Postal Service Tour with Mo. 1985 (Box 739, Folder 2)
    - Udall Photographs: Governor Felix Valdes of Sonora Visit. 1985 (Box 739, Folder 3)
    - Udall Photographs: Dedication Ceremony/Udall Portrait/Chairman of the House Interior Committee, Washington DC. 1985 (Box 739, Folder 4)
    - Udall Photographs: Negatives/Mo Udall and Senator Dodd/Fundraising Dinner, Doubletree Inn, Tucson. June 29, 1986 (Box 739, Folder 5)
    - Udall Photographs: Mo Udall, Honorary Doctorate. No Date (Box 739, Folder 6)
    - Udall Photographs: Mo Udall, San Pedro. 1987 (Box 739, Folder 7)
    - Udall Photographs: Interior Committee. 1988 (Box 739, Folder 8)
    - Udall Photographs: Michael Dukakis, Presidential Campaign. 1988 (Box 739, Folder 9)
    - Udall Photographs: Acid Rain Press Conference. 1989 (Box 739, Folder 10)
    - Udall Photographs: Bush Inauguration. 1989 (Box 739, Folder 11)
    - Udall Photographs: Udall Visits Special Collections. Spring 1990 (Box 739, Folder 12)
    - Udall Photographs: Mo with Senator Bradley/Representatives McMillan & Bunning/Jock Caucus. July 1990 (Box 739, Folder 13)
    - Udall Photographs: Mo Udall. 1990s (Box 739, Folder 14)
    - Udall Photographs: Point Udall, Guam. 1990s (Box 739, Folder 15)
    - Udall Photographs: Mo Udall Exhibit/Capital/Washington DC. 1991 (Box 739, Folder 16)
    - Udall Photographs: Oversize Photographs, General. (Box 740)
    - Udall Photographs: Oversize Photographs-Press Campaign; Favorite Son. 1976 and 1983 (Box 741)
    - Udall Photographs: Oversize Photographs-Photos, Posters, Miscellaneous. (Box 742)
    - Udall Photographs: Oversize Photographs-Photos, Posters. (Box 743)
    - Oversize Photographs: Arizona Justices-Levi Udall, Don Udall, Jessie Udall and Nick Udall. 1950s (Box 744, Folder 1)
    - Oversize Photographs: Stewart Udall-Secretary of the Interior. Circa 1965 (Box 744, Folder 2)
    - Oversize Photographs: Stewart Udall and Edward J. Robinson. Circa 1965 (Box 744, Folder 3)
    - Oversize Photographs: Mo Udall-Dinner Tribute, Tucson Arizona. 1966 (Box 744, Folder 4)
    - Oversize Photographs: Stewart Udall, Secretary of the Interior Dinner. Circa 1966 (Box 744, Folder 5)
    - Oversize Photographs: Central Arizona Project Signing, President Johnson. 1986 (Box 744, Folder 6)
    - Oversize Photographs: Stewart Udall, President Johnson. September 30, 1968 (Box 744, Folder 7)
    - Oversize Photographs: Prayer Breakfast, Washington DC. February 1970 (Box 744, Folder 8)
    - Oversize Photographs: Mo Udall Baseball. 1973 (Box 744, Folder 9)
    - Oversize Photographs: Will and Mo, The Great Story Tellers. 1975 (Box 744, Folder 10)
    - Oversize Photographs: Presidential Campaign, New York. 1976 (Box 744, Folder 11)
    - Oversize Photographs: David King Udall, St. John's Homestead. 1880 (Box 745, Folder 1)
    - Oversize Photographs: David King and Eliza Udall, 50th Wedding Anniversary. 1925 (Box 745, Folder 2)
    - Oversize Photographs: Mo Udall, Basketball, St. John's. 1935 (Box 745, Folder 3)
    - Oversize Photographs: Stewart Udall, Basketball, St. John's. 1935 (Box 745, Folder 4)
    - Oversize Photographs: Mo Udall. Circa 1936-1937 (Box 745, Folder 5)
    - Oversize Photographs: Stewart Udall, Basketball. 1939-1940 (Box 745, Folder 6)
    - Oversize Photographs: Mo Udall Cutting Stewart's Hair, St. John's. Circa 1940 (Box 745, Folder 7)
    - Oversize Photographs: Stewart Udall, University of Arizona Basketball. 1946-1947 (Box 745, Folder 8)
    - Oversize Photographs: Udall Family, St. John's Arizona. 1940s (Box 745, Folder 9)
    - Oversize Photographs: Udall Family, St. John's Arizona. Circa 1940 (Box 745, Folder 10)
    - Oversize Photographs: Presidential Campaign (Mo and Stewart Udall). 1976 (Box 745, Folder 11)
    - Oversize Photographs: Public Land Review Commission. September1969 (Box 746, Folder 1)
    - Oversize Photographs: Interior Commission, 91st Congress. 1969-1970 (Box 746, Folder 2)
    - Oversize Photographs: Interior Commission, 92nd Congress. 1971-1972 (Box 746, Folder 3)
    - Oversize Photographs: Interior Commission, 93rd Congress. 1973-1974 (Box 746, Folder 4)
    - Oversize Photographs: Foreign Affairs Committee Visit to Northern Europe. June-July 1985 (Box 746, Folder 5)
    - Oversize Photographs: House Committee Visit to Soviet Union. September 1985 (Box 746, Folder 6)
    - Oversize Photographs: Interior Committee. 1985 (Box 746, Folder 7)
  - Clippings and Scrapbooks, 1958-1985
    Arranged chronologically. Contains newspaper clippings from Arizona and out-of-state newspapers about Morris K. Udall, documenting his election campaigns and activities as a Congressman. Several of the volumes contain clippings documenting the political activities of Stewart Udall as a Congressman and later, Secretary of the Interior in the Kennedy and Johnson administrations. Also includes scattered clippings documenting the political activities of United States Senators Carl Hayden, Barry Goldwater, Paul Fannin, and Congressman John Rhodes. The clippings are in poor condition. They will be microfilmed in the future.
    - Scrapbooks, 27 Volumes. 1958-1981 (Box 747)
    - Loose Clippings: Morris K Udall. 1950s (Box 748, Folder 1)
    - Loose Clippings: Morris K Udall. 1960s (Box 748, Folder 2)
    - Loose Clippings: Morris K Udall. 1970s (Box 748, Folder 3-5)
    - Loose Clippings: Morris K Udall. 1980s (Box 748, Folder 6)
    - Clippings: Anti-Huff Clippings/Comments, 96th Congress. 1979-1980 (Box 748, Folder 7)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall, 97th Congress. 1981 (Box 748, Folder 8)
    - Clippings: Miscellaneous, 97th Congress. 1982 (Box 748, Folder 9-10)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. January-March 1982 (Box 748, Folder 11)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. April-June 1982 (Box 748, Folder 12)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. July-September 1982 (Box 748, Folder 13)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. October-December (Box 748, Folder 14)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. January-March 1983 (Box 749, Folder 1)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. April-June 1983 (Box 749, Folder 2)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. July-September 1983 (Box 749, Folder 3)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. October-December 1983 (Box 749, Folder 4)
    - Clippings: Nuclear Energy. 1983 (Box 749, Folder 5)
    - Clippings: Udall's Non-Candidacy for President. 1983 (Box 749, Folder 6)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. January-March 1984 (Box 749, Folder 7)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. April-May 1984 (Box 749, Folder 8)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. April-July 1984 (Box 749, Folder 9)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. June 1984 (Box 749, Folder 10)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. July-August 1984 (Box 749, Folder 11-12)
    - Clippings. September-December 1984 (Box 750, Folder 1)
    - Clippings: Mo Udall. 1984 (Box 750, Folder 2)
    - Clippings: Democratic National Convention. 1984 (Box 750, Folder 3)
    - Clippings: Richard Nixon. 1984 (Box 750, Folder 4)
    - Clippings: Three Mile Island. 1984 (Box 750, Folder 5)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. 1985 (Box 750, Folder 6)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. January-March 1984 (Box 750, Folder 7)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. April-June 1985 (Box 750, Folder 8)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. July-December 1985 (Box 750, Folder 9)
    - Clippings: Udall News Summary. 1985 (Box 750, Folder 10)
    - Clippings: Nuclear Clippings. 1985 (Box 750, Folder 11-12)
    - Clippings: Tennessee Valley Authority. 1985 (Box 750, Folder 13)
    - Clippings. 1986 (Box 750, Folder 14-15)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. January-March 1986 (Box 750, Folder 16)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. April-June 1986 (Box 750, Folder 17)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. September-December 1986 (Box 750, Folder 18)
    - Clippings: Congressional Income. 1986-1988 (Box 750, Folder 19)
    - Clippings: Indians. 1986-1989 (Box 750, Folder 20)
    - Clippings: Tennessee Valley Authority. January 22-March 9, 1986 (Box 750, Folder 21)
    - Clippings: Tennessee Valley Authority Articles. April-May 1986 (Box 750, Folder 22)
    - Clippings: Tennessee Valley Authority Articles. June-December 1986 (Box 750, Folder 23)
    - Clippings: Udall News Summary. January-June 1986 (Box 751, Folder 1-2)
    - Clippings: Udall News Summary. July-December 1986 (Box 751, Folder 3-4)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. January-June 1986 (Box 751, Folder 5)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. July-December 1986 (Box 751, Folder 6)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. 1987-1989 (Box 751, Folder 7)
    - Clippings: Udall Center Public Policy Studies. 1987-1988 (Box 751, Folder 8)
    - Clippings. 1987 (Box 751, Folder 9)
    - Clippings: Miscellaneous. 1987-1988 (Box 751, Folder 10)
    - Clippings: Energy. 1987 (Box 751, Folder 11)
    - Clippings: Mecham Recall. 1987-1988 (Box 751, Folder 12)
    - Clippings: Soviet Student Exchange. 1987 (Box 751, Folder 13)
    - Clippings: Tennessee Valley Authority. 1987 (Box 751, Folder 14)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. 1988 (Box 751, Folder 15)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. January-June 1988 (Box 751, Folder 16)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. July-September 1988 (Box 751, Folder 17)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. October-December 1988 (Box 751, Folder 18)
    - Clippings: Campaign. 1988 (Box 751, Folder 19)
    - Clippings: Phoenix District Office, Miscellaneous. 1988 (Box 751, Folder 20)
    - Clippings: Tennessee Valley Authority. 1988 (Box 752, Folder 1)
    - Clippings: Miscellaneous. 1989 (Box 752, Folder 2-4)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. 1989 (Box 752, Folder 5)
    - Clippings: Campaign Finance Bill. 1989 (Box 752, Folder 6)
    - Clippings: Congressional Pay Raise. 1989-1990 (Box 752, Folder 7)
    - Clippings: Defense Spending and Tucson. 1989-1990 (Box 752, Folder 8)
    - Clippings: Dollar Coin. 1989-1990 (Box 752, Folder 9)
    - Clippings: Drug War. 1989-1990 (Box 752, Folder 10)
    - Clippings: Environment. 1989-1990 (Box 752, Folder 11)
    - Clippings: Military Academy Appointments. 1989-1990 (Box 752, Folder 12)
    - Clippings: Mount Graham. 1989-1990 (Box 752, Folder 13)
    - Clippings: Parkinson's Disease. 1989-1990 (Box 752, Folder 14)
    - Clippings: Patriotism. 1989-1990 (Box 752, Folder 15)
    - Clippings: San Carlos Lake Fish. 1989-1990 (Box 752, Folder 16)
    - Clippings: Udall Park. 1989-1990 (Box 752, Folder 17)
    - Clippings: Phoenix District Office, Miscellaneous. 1989 (Box 752, Folder 18)
    - Clippings: Miscellaneous. 1990 (Box 752, Folder 19-20)
    - Clippings: Arizona Wilderness Bill. 1990 (Box 752, Folder 21)
    - Clippings: Morris K Udall. 1990 (Box 752, Folder 22)
    - Clippings: Nuclear Energy. 1990 (Box 752, Folder 23)
    - Clippings: Phoenix District Office, Miscellaneous. 1991-1992 (Box 752, Folder 24)
    - Clippings: Phoenix District Office, Miscellaneous. 1991-1992 (Box 752, Folder 25-26)
  - Questionnaires, 1963-1990
    Arranged chronologically and by Congress. Contains opinion questionnaires sent by Morris K. Udall to constituents, flyers describing the questionnaires, drafts of questionnaires prepared by Morris K Udall and staff, computer printouts with tabulated answers, Congressional Record inserts describing the results of the questionnaires, notes and correspondence related to the questionnaires. The questionnaires relate to major issues of the period including Vietnam, CAP, firearms legislation, direct election of the President, public disclosure, 18 year old voting age, volunteer army, taxes and campaign financing. Also contains correspondence with public opinion polling consultants. Weeded from this series were duplicates and questionnaire paste-ups. The bulk of the correspondence consisted of simple thank-yous from Morris K. Udall to the constituents. A 10% sample of this correspondence and a 1% sample of the returned questionnaires were retained.
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 87th Congress, Farm Legislation. 1961-1962 (Box 753, Folder 1)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 88th Congress. 1963 (Box 753, Folder 2)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 89th Congress. 1964 (Box 753, Folder 3)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 90th Congress. 1967-1968 (Box 753, Folder 4)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 90th Congress, Questions, Correspondence-Gun Control, Pro-/Con. 1967-1968 (Box 753, Folder 5-6)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 90th Congress, Questions-Draft. 1967-1968 (Box 753, Folder 7-11)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 90th Congress, Questions. 1968 (Box 753, Folder 12-14)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 91st Congress, Legislative Questions. 1969-1970 (Box 753, Folder 15)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 92nd Congress, Legislative Questions. December 1971 (Box 753, Folder 16-17)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 92nd Congress, Questionnaire. 1971-1972 (Box 753, Folder 18-20)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 92nd Congress, Robo Correspondence. 1971-1972 (Box 753, Folder 21)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: Letters. 1971-1972 (Box 753, Folder 22)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 93rd Congress. 1973-1974 (Box 754, Folder 1-3)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 94th Congress. 1975-1976 (Box 754, Folder 4-5)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 94th Congress, Responses. 1975-1976 (Box 754, Folder 6)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 94th Congress, Comments. 1975-1976 (Box 754, Folder 7)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 95th Congress. 1977-1978 (Box 754, Folder 8)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 95th Congress, Comments. 1977-1978 (Box 754, Folder 9)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 96th Congress. 1979-1980 (Box 754, Folder 10)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 98th Congress-Media. 1983-1984 (Box 754, Folder 11)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 99th Congress. 1985-1986 (Box 754, Folder 12-13)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 100th Congress. 1987-1990 (Box 754, Folder 14-16)
    - Legislative Questionnaires: 101st Congress. 1989-1990 (Box 754, Folder 17-18)
  - Freshman Seminar, 1959-1969
    Contains material relating to the Freshman Seminars begun by Stewart Udall and others in the late 50s. These seminars were intended to familiarize freshman Congressmen with the inner workings of the U.S. Congress. Contains correspondence, offprints, notes and memos relating to the topic. Documents Morris K. Udall's involvement.
    - Freshman Seminar. 1959-1966 (Box 755)
    - Freshman Seminar. 1967-1969 (Box 755)
  - Memorabilia, 1946-1985
    Contains awards, diplomas and other three-dimensional objects given to Morris K. Udall in recognition of achievements and activities.
    - Memorabilia: (Box 756)
      T-shirts
      Buttons
      Small Plaques
      Coins
      Awards
      Medals
      Pins
      Dukakis Necktie
      Automobile License Plants,
      Keys
      Udall ID
      Table Place Cards for Heritage Award Dinner In Tucson, November 18, 1994
    - Memorabilia: Donkey Collection. (Box 757)
    - Memorabilia. (Box 758)
      Campaign buttons
      Louise Udall Pamphlet
      Bumper Stickers
      Channel 4 News Scripts
      Program: Red Hills Visitor's Center Dedication
      Duval Hard Hat
      Various Dinner Programs
      Indian Drum Award
      Morris K. Udall Plaque Information Flyer
      Miscellaneous.
    - Memorabilia: Political Cartoons (Two Framed). (Box 759)
    - Memorabilia: Political Cartoons (Four Framed). (Box 760)
    - Memorabilia: National Jewish Hospital Award/Scrapbook; Mo Udall Day, St. John's, Arizona. April 19, 1983 and July 4, 1980 (Box 761)
    - Memorabilia: Award Plaques. (Box 762-766)
    - Memorabilia. (Box 767)
      Central Arizona Project Putter
      Coconut Mail
      University of Arizona Letter Sweater and Watch
      1976 Presidential Campaign/Wisconsin Primary Banner
    - Memorabilia: Oversize Posters, Awards, Political Ads. 1970-1980s (Box 768)
    - Memorabilia: Campaign Posters, Awards, Political Ads. 1960-1980s (Box 769)
    - Memorabilia: Miscellaneous, Painting, Posters. (Box 770)
    - Memorabilia: Oversized Award Plaques. (Box 771)
  - Pre-Congressional Activity Files, 1946-1975
    Contains correspondence, reminiscences, real-estate, records, financial records, and other materials relating largely to Morris K. Udall's career and personal interests outside of his congressional duties. Includes Louise Udall's account of Morris K. Udall's eye loss, three files from his office as Pima County Attorney, and correspondence related to the publication of his books Evidence, Trial Practice, and The Education of a Congressman.
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Band Music. 1930s (Box 772, Folder 1)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Draft Board. 1942 (Box 772, Folder 2)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: U.S. Army Clipping-Sports. 1942-1944 (Box 772, Folder 3)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Student Body President, University of Arizona. 1947 (Box 772, Folder 4)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Reminiscence by Louise Udall on Morris' Eye Accident. (Box 772, Folder 5)
    - Desert 1947 Morris Udall's University of Arizona Yearbook. 1947 (Box 772, Folder 6)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: University of Arizona Basketball, Tucson City League. 1947 (Box 772, Folder 7)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Program, Denver Nuggets vs. Waterloo Hawks. December 14, 1948 (Box 772, Folder 8)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Denver Nuggets. 1948 (Box 772, Folder 9)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Udall and Udall Law Firm, Tucson, Clipping. (Box 772, Folder 10)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Tucson Citizens Housing Committee. 1949 (Box 772, Folder 11)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: City-County Cooperation. 1952-1954 (Box 772, Folder 12)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Deputy County Attorney. 1952 (Box 772, Folder 13)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Property, 222 N. Court. (Box 772, Folder 14)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Modern Courts Amendment No.101- Improving the Administration of Justice. and Clippings. (Box 772, Folder 15)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Court Statistics (Box 772, Folder 16)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Criminal Motions and Instructions. (Box 772, Folder 17)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities Election Phase. (Box 772, Folder 18)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Jury Lists. (Box 772, Folder 19)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Miscellaneous. (Box 772, Folder 20)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Article IV, Legislative Package. (Box 772, Folder 21)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Pamphlets and Papers. (Box 772, Folder 22)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Thompson/Dodd Proposals. (Box 772, Folder 23)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Levi Udall Estate 1945-1962 (Box 772, Folder 24)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Land Syndicate. 1961-1965 (Box 772, Folder 25)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Property, 5055 Calle La Vela. 1963 (Box 772, Folder 26)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Sarti vs. Udall Lawsuit. 1963 (Box 772, Folder 27)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Universal Service Life Insurance. 1964-1966 (Box 772, Folder 28-29)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Property, Ashley Terrace, Washington DC. 1964-1966 (Box 772, Folder 30)
    - Pre-Congressional Activities: Property, Lakeview Estates, Virginia. 1968 (Box 772, Folder 31)